KATRINA TSUKUDA

San Francisco, CA kat.tsukuda@gmail.com (408) 307-5289

Digital campaigner, marketer, and analyst with over 9 years of experience in fundraising, outreach and communications, and program and project management for environmental, health, international affairs and public policy non-profit organizations.

SKILLS

Tools

CRM platforms (Convio, Salesforce); MS Word, Excel, Outlook, and PowerPoint; Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator; SEO (BrightEdge); Publishing (WordPress & Medium); A/B, Multivariate-Testing, and Website Customization (Optimizely); and Google Analytics and AdWords.

Digital Communications

Social Media (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, etc.); SMS (Mobile Commons); Affiliate Marketing (Print & Display Ads, Partner Emails, Content Blogs, Radio Spots, etc.)

Languages

HTML, CSS, and working knowledge of JavaScript and jQuery.

Beginner Proficiency in Spanish and French, and working knowledge of Arabic and Japanese.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY 2014, San Francisco, CA

Digital Marketing

DE ANZA COLLEGE 2011-2012, Cupertino, CA Graphic Design and French

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON 2010, London, UK

M.A., Human Rights

UC SANTA CRUZ 2005-2009, Santa Cruz, CA

B.A., Politics with Honors

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Consultant San Francisco, CA Digital Content and Strategy Specialist

February 2017 - Present

- Provide data driven campaign strategy and digital marketing services to clients focused on social change and environmental issues.
- Develop digital design and written content for social media, websites/blogs, and paid search and display ads.

CREDO MOBILE San Francisco, CA

February 2016 - January 2017

Digital Affiliates and Campaigns Manager

- Spearheaded multi-channel campaign launches with CREDO Mobile's Marketing (Email, Customer Growth, and Retention), Donations, and Actions departments and progressive media and non-profit partners: Daily Kos, Democrats.com, Inside Climate News, Mother Jones, The Nation, Think Progress, Planned Parenthood, Sierra Club, Southern Poverty Law Center, etc.
- Built and managed variants for A/B and multivariate testing to optimize CREDOMobile. com, landing pages, and paid search and display ads.
- Nurtured and developed Mobile partnerships for CREDO Mobile, Action, and Donations to increase list-growth, sales, and affiliate marketing partnerships.
- Help exceed monthly mobile sales goals by 8-12 percent during peak holiday seasons and the annual list-growth goal by 18 percent, adding over 1.3 million actively engaged members to CREDO's email list in 2016.

GREENPEACE USA San Francisco, CA Online Campaigner & Graphic Designer

August 2014 - February 2016

- Liaised with an integrated team of stakeholders to develop and implement digital content strategy for environmental campaigns for climate and energy, the Arctic, oceans, and forests.
- Developed dashboards and monitors to provide reports with analysis and recommendations to optimize the performance of paid advertisements and social media, website, and email content.
- Established metrics and Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) to identify target demographics for campaigns, fundraising efforts, and lead generation.
- Wrote compelling copy and designed high impact graphics for email, SMS, social media, and greenpeace.org and its microsites to engage and grow GP's 1 million+movement to take action and donate.

HUMAN RIGHTS WATCH San Francisco, CA Development & Global Initiatives Consultant

April 2014 - June 2014

- Produced research and analysis on the financial capacity and philanthropic history and inclination of on prospective major gift donors.
- Collaborated with an integrated team of stakeholders, primarily in Western Europe and Australia, in an effort to enhance the organization's global presence and philanthropic support.

KATRINA TSUKUDA

San Francisco, CA kat.tsukuda@gmail.com (408) 307-5289

ACHIEVEMENTS

UC WASHINGTON CENTER 2009, Washington, DC

Awarded a scholarship for an independent research and internship program.

MEIJI GAKUIN UNIVERSITY 2008, Yokohama, Japan

Foreign Exchange Student in the Global and International Studies Program.

INSTITUTE FOR HUMANE STUDIES 2007, Arlington, VA

Awarded a scholarship for the Globalization, Technology & Development Summer Seminar.

INTERESTS

Social movements, hiking, traveling, graphic design, singing, learning foreign languages, volunteering, baking, and salvaging.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

THE TRUST FOR PUBLIC LAND San Francisco, CA Prospect Research Analyst

September 2012 - August 2014

- Provided pro-active, consistent and actionable analysis to an integrated team of stakeholders in an effort to optimize the organization's overall fundraising goals, most notably for a \$400 million campaign.
- Interpreted complex financial and legal disclosures, technical and trade documents; and evaluate wealth indicators, including income and other assets.
- Conceptualized and developed donor identification and retention strategies through constituent list segmentation, data mining, electronic database screening, and peer/ constituency screening and rating.
- Utilized database to review donors, produce queries and reports, and audit and update records.

DE ANZA COLLEGE Cupertino, CA Reading & Writing Tutor

2012

- · Worked with English Language Learners to develop critical reading and writing skills.
- Identified and addressed structural, grammatical and sentence-level concerns by providing editing resources and strategies.

INTERNATIONAL RESCUE COMMITTEE San Francisco, CA English Tutor & Job Development Volunteer

2012

Assisted refugees with the development of critical listening, speaking, reading and writing skills in English; and searching and preparing for employment opportunities.

HUMAN RIGHTS WATCH San Francisco, CA Prospect Research Intern

2011

- Provided detailed research and financial analysis on high net worth domestic and international individuals, corporations, and foundations to assist in the development of specific fundraising strategies.
- Monitor business and financial news outlets to identify and track potential donors.

BAY AREA CLIMATE COLLABORATIVE San Francisco, CA Program and Communications Coordinator

2011

- Liaised with local government and corporate partners to launch and promote clean and renewable energy initiatives around solar energy and LEED standards for green building within the San Francisco Bay Area.
- Produced marketing collateral and research materials on energy efficiency initiatives.
- Managed the organization's website and email outreach, including producing and posting web content and producing and sending email blasts.

National Women's Law Center Washington, DC Outreach Coordinator

2011

- Authored action alerts, opinion pieces, and policy updates for the organization's blog, Womenstake.org, on women's policy issues in education, employment, health and reproduction.
- Participated in press conferences and lobbying campaigns and attended and drafted summary notes from legislation hearings for the Health Care Reform Act.
- Conducted issue-based blogger research and outreach.
- Coordinated the planning and organization of materials for the annual Law Students for Reproductive Justice training program.

201